Criminal. Class.
The Gentlemen is a comedy, crime film directed by Guy Ritchie.
American expat Mickey Pearson has built a highly
profitable marijuana empire in London.
When word gets out that he’s looking to cash out of the business forever it triggers plots,
schemes, bribery and blackmail in an attempt to steal his domain out from under him.
Michael Pearson, played by Matthew McConaughey.
Ray, played by Charlie Hunnam.
Rosalind Pearson, played by Michelle Dockery.
Matthew, played by Jeremy Strong.
Jackie, played by Lyne Renee.
Coach, played by Colin Farrell.
The Gentlemen is a 2019 action comedy film, directed and produced by Guy
Ritchie, co-written with Marn Davies and Ivan Atkinson.
Starring Matthew McConaughey, Charlie Hunnam, Henry Golding, Michelle Dockery, Jeremy Strong, Eddie Marsan, Colin Farrell, and Hugh Grant, the film
follows an American drug lord in England who is looking to sell his business, setting off a chain of blackmail and schemes to undermine him.
The Gentlemen premiered at the Curzon Mayfair Cinema on 3 December 2019, and was released in cinemas in the United Kingdom on
1 January 2020, by Entertainment Film Distributors, and in the United States on 24 January 2020, by STXfilms.
It received generally positive reviews from critics and was also a commercial
success, grossing $115 million worldwide against its $22 million budget.
A spin-off television series was released by Netflix in 2024
with Theo James starring in the lead role.
The film explores themes of london, england, robbery,
businessman, gangster, dark comedy.
The tone is lighthearted and dark.